强尼戴普
醉后型男日记
波多黎各联合碳化物欢迎你莅临
- 是谁呢？ - 客房服务。
- Who is it? - Room service.
是鸡蛋吗？
Is it eggs?
我不知道，先生。不是我点的。
I don't know, sir. I didn't order it.
你想要开水吗？
You want some water with that?
不...。 不，我不要。
No, no. No, I don't.
看起来你有一个销魂夜呃。
Looks like you had a night.
看起来很完美。
They look perfect.
滚出去。
Get out.
我本打算叫服务人员来的。
I intended to bring that to the attention of a member of staff.
我打开时遇到了一些困难。
I had some difficulty getting it to open.
小钥匙挂在房门钥匙里，先生。
It's the little key on the door key, sir.
是呃。
Right.
我一直在找一些坚果。
I was looking for some nuts.
我想尽量避免喝酒。
I tend to avoid alcohol.
有酒喝，我是可以的。
When I can.
我不会讲西班牙语。
I don't speak Spanish.
四十五块。 不找零。
Cuatro cincuenta. No change.
不... 你没在听。
No, no, no, no, you're not listening.
我说海盗，不是洋基。
I said the Pirates, not the Yankees.
我告诉你，今年将是罗伯托年。
It's going to be Roberto's year, I'm telling you.
找莱特曼先生。
Looking for Mr. Letterman.
最后那间。
End of the room.
不，不，海盗。
No, no, the Pirates.
你们这些人会搞砸了。
You guys are going to be all over.
是罗伯托克莱门特，老兄。
It's Roberto Clemente, man.
还有，我想谈谈 ...
And by the way, I want to talk about...
没空！
Not now!
他的周五危机。
He's having the Friday crisis.
- 坎普？ - 是啊。
- You Kemp? - Yeah.
他昨天在等你耶。
He was expecting you yesterday.
气候不佳。
We had some weather.
是的，我有听说。
Yeah, I heard.
在纽约的大风雪。
Big snow in New York.
他仍然在通电话。想喝点咖啡吗？
He's still on a call. You want some coffee?
不，谢谢。
No, thanks.
前门在吵什么？
What's all the fuss out front?
你走前门？
You came in the front?
我们不走前门。
We don't use that door.
当洛.吉巴度涨不起来时。
Not when los jibaros pitch up.
他们抗争什么？
What do they want?
我不知道。
I don't know.
为了工资想了一些鬼主意。
Some fucked idea of a living wage.
他们在那里闹了好几个月。
They've been out there on and off for months.
对了，我的名字叫萨拉。
By the way, my name's Sala.
鲍勃撒拉，摄影师。
Bob Sala, staff photographer.
很高兴见到你，鲍勃。
Pleased to meet you, Bob.
是啊。
Yeah.
他好了。
He's off.
你可以试着轻轻的敲门。
You might want to try another subservient knock.
是啊。
Yeah.
坎普。
Kemp.
不要提到假发呃。
Don't notice the wig.
是啊。 什么事？
Yeah. What?
如果你是我想找的人，最好坐下。
If you're who I think you are, you better sit down.
你觉得这里太亮了吗？
You find it a little bright in here?
眼镜要摘下来吗？我眼睛有点毛病。
I'd take them off, but I have a medical condition.
你是什??么意思，你瞎了吗？
What do you mean, you're blind?
结膜炎，长官。
Conjunctivitis, sir.
红眼症，是吧？
The old red eye, huh?
你遇到一个非常艰困的时刻，坎普先生。
You arrive at a very, very trying time, Mr. Kemp.
陈年堆积而成的。
One of those days stacking up.
那么，我们为何不去繁从简，就事论事，对吧？
So, why don't we cut through the niceties and just get right to it, huh?
这就是我想做的。
That's how I like to proceed.
好了。你的简历在这里。
Okay. Your resume here.
令人印象深刻。
Very impressive CV.
是啊。
Yeah.
你有自己的做法及有趣的标题。
You worked your way up some interesting titles.
我喜欢“一口流利的西班牙语。”
I really like the "fluent Spanish."
哇。
Wow.
这简历是一堆废话。
This CV is a bunch of bullshit.
是呃？
Ls it?
这是两天前上线的。
This is two days on the wire.
一天就完了。 我们没得玩了。
A day dead. We don't have it.
默巴克在搞什么？
What is the matter with Moburg?
他有苛Φ耐诳找磺小
He's about as useful as a dug-up body.
你看，报纸上的问题，坎普先生，
You see, the problem with this newspaper, Mr. Kemp,
是我在许多报导里最不想见到的。
is that I am among many who don't enjoy reading it.
我们在流通有一个病因，
We have an ailing circulation,
我只能以井窥天的去理解。
and I just have to look around this building to understand why.
缺乏承诺和太多的自我放纵。
Lack of commitment and too much self-indulgence.
所以我要找
So what I'm looking for
一些热情，一些能源，
is some enthusiasm, some energy,
一些新血。
some fresh blood.
问题是，我常扪心自问
And the question that I'm asking myself
通常你体内有多少酒精。
is how much alcohol is usual in yours.
我的血液中？
My fresh blood?
你喝多少酒？
How much do you drink?
我想在上次的“社交”。
I suppose at the upper end of "social."
准备戒酒。
I'm poised to give up.
当然，波多黎各不是戒酒的好地方。
Well, Puerto Rico may not be the best place on Earth to do that.
没必要焦虑不安，坎普先生。
Don't look so anxious, Mr. Kemp.
在聘用之前，我是不会支付酒店的任何费用。
I wouldn't have paid for your hotel if I hadn't already hired you.
但这不是最后上车的机会，
But this is not the Last Chance Saloon,
我不需要另一个借酒浇愁。
and I do not need another heavy drinker.
我的条件，是眼镜背后的“眼光”，
Which I perceive, from the condition of eyeballs behind glasses,
你很可能够资格。
that you might very well qualify as.
这是眼疾的问题，莱特曼先生。
This is a medical condition, Mr. Letterman.
我知道，看起来像似，但这..
I know it might look like something else, but this is a...
其实就是“宿醉”
Looks like a fuckin' hangover.
是吗？
Does it?
来这里。
Come here.
我乐意见到一个守承诺的人。
That's the kind of commitment I like to see in a man.
判断力，融合力，恰如其份的人。
Determination, balanced with appropriate humanity.
啊，是啊，是啊，是啊，是啊。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你看好哪一方，坎普？
Which side do you dress, Kemp?
对不起？
I beg your pardon?
政治。
Politics.
我是中间派的。
I kind of hang in the middle.
这是一个精神分裂的社会，坎普。
This is a schizoid society, Kemp.
两种语言，两种标志，两种忠诚，两种国歌。
They got two languages, two flags, two loyalties, two anthems.
带给他们的，也是从未有过的。
We bring them stuff they never had.
他们是又恨又爱。
They either hate it or they want more of it.
这是美国最厌恶的部份。
It's a reluctant part of America.
就像长在英格兰的热带水果。
It's like an England with tropical fruit.
鲍勃。
Bob.
我想要的人选。
Just the man I wanted to see.
这是保罗.坎普。   他是纽约来的新伙伴。
This is Paul Kemp. He's joining us from New York.
啊，是啊，已经照过面了。
Yeah, yeah, we already met.
这是克莱夫多诺万先生，体育部。
That's Mr. Clive Donovan, sports.
这是休伯特先生，会计。
And this is Mr. Hubert, accounting.
听着，帮个忙，可以吗？
Listen, do me a favor, will you?
带他逛逛，该做那些事。
Show him around, the dos and don'ts.
介绍给大家认识。
Introduce him to some of the guys.
我带他去找艾尔。
I'll take him up to Al's.
一定要。  会的。
The hell you will.
你带他去资料库。
You take him to the library.
找一些卷宗。
You pull out some volumes.
我要他找些有意义的文件。
I want him to get a sense of the paper.
知道吧，做些注解，在过去几年内，
You know, make some notes, go back a few years,
要特别注意保龄球馆。
paying particular attention to bowling alleys.
有保龄球和保龄球馆。
There's bowling and bowling alleys.
这里非常大。 如雨后春笋般。
Very big here. They're up like mushrooms.
每周一报。
A new one premieres every week.
- 在波多黎各之前？ - 不。
- Been to Puerto Rico before? - No.
你会乐在其中。
You're going to fall right into it.
这里很繁忙，坎普。 是很开放的。
There's a boom on here, Kemp. It's an open door.
你做对了，就能步步高升。
You play it right, you can surf the place.
你知道占星术吗？
What do you know about horoscopes?
不知道。
Nothing.
那么，我可以写，你也可以。
Well, if I can write one, you can.
所以，每天都用特殊的“星之星”
So it's every day with a special "Star's Star"
星期六的主题是贝蒂.葛莱柏，
featured Saturday with Betty Grable
和尼尔.沙达克，之类的东西。
and Neil Sedaka, things like that.
所以，你需要的全部在这里。
So here, everything you need is right there.
这就是所谓的“鲁佐女士的预测”
It's called "Madam La Zonga Predicts."
“鲁佐女士”发生了什么事？？
What happened to Madam La Zonga?
她被取消了。
He got canceled.
你的意思是，炒尤鱼？
What do you mean, fired?
她被奸杀。
They raped him to death.
她被奸杀吗？
They raped him to death?
在这里有极少数的岛，
There are very few places on this island
是禁止访问的。
I decline to visit,
但厕所经常是水手在利用。
but the toilets frequented by sailors
甘达多码头西侧是其中之一。
on the west side of Candado Pier is one.
水手奸杀她吗？
They raped him to death?
鲁佐死在一个小隔间内。
La Zonga died in a cubicle.
我说，你不是艺术家，坎普，你是吗？
Say, you're not artistic, are you, Kemp?
哦，不是。
Oh, no.
你该考虑改抽薄荷卷烟。
You might want to rethink those menthol cigarettes.
否则，你可能没烟抽。
They don't do a thing for you.
有空到我家来。
Come by the house.
我会的。
I will.
我喜欢你的题材。
I like your stuff.
你发送给莱特曼的插文。
The cuttings you sent to Letterman.
写的不错。
It's good writing.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我们再讨论。
We'll talk.
再一层！
One more floor!
大约半年前改成自动化包装。
They put in automated packing machines about six months ago.
机械化几乎无所不能。
They mechanized almost everything.
以前要50个人，现在只要5个。
There used to be 50 guys down here. Now there's five.
于是街上洋溢着失业的幸福。
Hence happiness in the street.
纪念品，每日一爆。
Souvenir, day one.
这里的美女都有肮脏的想法。
Here's to pretty women with filthy thoughts.
- 要一个汉堡？ - 不要
- Want a burger? - No.
- 汉堡？ - 不，谢谢。
- Burger? - No, thanks.
试试吧。   两个。
Try it. Dos.
所以，该如何归纳？
So how was the induction?
有点误人子弟。
Somewhat fraught.
无不敬，保罗，他没有太多的选择。
No disrespect, Paul, but he didn't have a lot of choice.
你知道有多少人申请工作吗？
You know how many people applied for the job?
一个。   你。
One. You.
是呃？
Ls that right?
即使这样，我还是要老王卖瓜。
Even then, I thought I'd blown it.
穷是我的弱点。
Zeroed in on my weakest spot.
怎么说？
Which is what?
2.5篇的虚构小说尚未发表。
Two and a half unpublished novels and references of equal fiction.
你是一个小说家。
You're a novelist.
在某种层面上来说。
In a manner of speaking.
还没完成。
Can't even get read.
所以我想先赚点钱，
So I figured I'd do some words for money,
在一年或两年的时间内。
see how it's looking in a year or two.
在艾尔之星吗？
At El Star?
我讨厌用这种说法，
Hate to tell you this on the way in,
但对出版物的发行。
but this publication's on its way out.
就我而言，不是说来就来的。
And as far as I'm concerned, it can't come soon enough.
不会这样的。
Not going to happen.
你喜欢那个小翁加公司吗？
You like a little vonga on that?
这件事从6月2日到13日。
I'll give you 13 to 2 this thing's over by June.
他们将进行断电。
They're going to cut the cord.
所有新的机器吗？
Then why put in all the new machinery?
这是重点，他却无能为力。
Precisely my point, and he can't answer it.
好吧，争论让我觉得很累。
Well, like I'm tired of arguing the obvious.
来吧。  我们吃东西。
Come on. Let's eat.
现在，我得去见一个人，谈谈有关马的事。
Now, I got to go and see a man about a horse.
很高兴见到你，保罗。
Good to meet you, Paul.
另一个华灯初上的老圣胡安夜晚。
Another night unfolds over Old San Juan.
你待在这里很久了吗？
You been here long?
太久了。
Too long.
这个地方真他妈的逊毙了
This place is like someone you fucked
死缠着你不放。
and they're still under you.
你为什么不退出呢？
Why don't you quit?
人生处处有出路。
Life's full of exits.
因为我只能等到倒闭，才能拿到的酬劳。
Because I'm waiting for it to collapse so I get the payoff.
三种压力让我留在墨西哥。
Three grand redundancy puts me in Mexico.
不要往左看。
Don't look left.
你最好不要认识他。
That's an introduction you don't want to have.
他是谁？
Who's he?
活生生的例子，与本报社的错误。
Living example of everything that's wrong with this paper.
他叫默博。
His name's Moburg.
我们犯罪和宗教事务的记者。
Our Crime and Religious Affairs correspondent.
莱特曼不能解雇他，因为从没见过他。
Letterman can't fire him because he never sees him.
他很少在白天出来。
He's rarely out in daylight.
他很喜欢喝酒。
Looks like he enjoys a drink.
满脑子存放的只是朗姆酒。
The entire substructure of his brain is eaten away with rum.
我告诉你，这家企业是注定要失败。
I'm telling you, this enterprise is doomed.
也许有三，四个专业人才在撑住报社。
There's maybe three or four professionals in the building running the entire show.
等等。     谁是哈尔.桑德森？
Wait a minute. Who is Hal Sanderson?
在资料库。   他是谁？
In the library. Who's he?
他的工作是管理文件。
He used to work for the paper.
现在，是，他说是什么公关顾问。
Now he's what he says he is. A PR consultant.
这个地方的销售由街到街直到洋基。
Selling this place street by street to the Yankees.
靠着一个叫西格拉的滑头小混蛋。
Keeps a greasy little bastard of a contact called Segurra.
我见过。  没有交谈。
I saw him. We didn't meet.
不用介意。
Wouldn't bother.
当作小便。
Piss on the make.
那小子，西格拉拥有不义之财。
The boy, Segurra, is at the property wickedness.
我不知道桑德森是否参与。
I'm not sure where Sanderson fits.
但桑德森是值得栽培的。
But Sanderson's worth cultivation.
他有一些良好的关系。
He's got some good connections.
他适合在自由业。
He's good for some freelance.
这里真令人沉闷，今晚除外。
This place is depressing me beyond belief tonight.
你住普来兹酒店，对吧？
You're at Plage Xanadu, right?
来吧。  我送你一程。
Come on. I'll give you a ride.
我在想，如果你需要在某处，
I was thinking, if you need somewhere,
我租的房间。
I got a room for rent.
在城里不是最佳的地点，但有冰箱和电视机。
Not the best address in town, but it's got a fridge and TV.
每个月60块。
60 a month.
听起来很诱人，我会考虑的。
Sounds inviting. I might remention that.
还有，别喝死了。
Meanwhile, bleed it dry.
先生...
Sir...
我想游泳。
I was hoping for a swim.
泳池今晚暂停。
The pool is closed tonight.
真的吗？ 为什么呢？ 这是怎么回事？
Really? Why? What's going on?
这是一个联合碳化物公司的派对。
It's a Union Carbide party.
这是一个私人的派对。
It's a private function.
对不起。
Sorry.
我不知道这里有人。
I didn't realize anyone was there.
我只是在这里浮泳。
I thought it was just floating.
只是浮泳。
It is just floating.
你干嘛，跟我一样啊？
You doing what I'm doing?
我不这么认为。
I don't think so.
那你在做什么呢？
What are you doing?
摆脱可怕的派对。
Escaping the dreadful party.
我只是想舒缓压力。
I just snuck out and unzipped.
是呃，你真有勇气。
Well, that's very courageous of you.
我还以为是美人鱼咧。
I thought maybe you were a mermaid.
他们告诉我美人鱼常在海岸出没。
They tell me the coast is infested with them.
我来自康涅狄格州。
I'm from Connecticut.
我男朋友的演说会。
My boyfriend's making a speech.
需要整整21分钟。
Takes exactly 21 minutes.
好吧，我想这很无聊的，我请你喝酒。
Well, then I guess it's pointless, me inviting you for a drink.
你有什么呢？
What you got?
不，我的意思是在酒吧。
No, I mean at the bar.
无聊。
Pointless.
在去之前，最好让他们知道我在哪里。
I'd better go before they wonder where I went.
等一下。你叫什么名字？
Wait a minute. What's your name?
让我们保守秘密。
Let's keep that a secret.
我没有你的任何资讯。
I don't even know it.
最好，你最好就是保持这样。
Well, then you'll keep it even better.
你是什么星座？
What about your star sign?
我是一位知名的天文学家。
I'm an experienced astronomer.
可以试试双鱼座。
Could try Pisces.
鱼啊。
The fish.
噢，天啊。
Oh, God.
她为什么要出现？
Why did she have to happen?
就当做我没有遇见过。
Just when I was doing so good without her.
波多黎各哪里最喜欢，你会怎么说呢？
What would you say you like most about Puerto Rico?
保龄球馆和赌场。
The bowling alleys and the casinos.
当然，她喜欢免税。
Course, she likes the duty free.
那么，你花越多，就省越多。
Well, the more you spend, the more you save.
你见过很多的岛屿吗？
Have you seen a lot of the island?
我们没离开酒店过。
We don't leave the hotel.
那是不安全的。
It isn't safe.
但这样有乐趣吗？
But you're having fun?
哦，是的！一种洛塔，洛塔的乐趣！
Oh, yeah! A lotta, lotta fun!
一些有趣的是他妈的卢杰。
Have some fun with a fucking Luger.
那些小巷对老饕很诱惑的。
These alleys are magnets to the glutton.
下船的人像蝗虫一样多。
They come off the boats like locusts.
肥胖猪头。
Beasts of obesity.
驴子感应不到箭头。
Asses that wouldn't feel an arrow.
伟大的白人。
The great whites.
可能是地球上最危险的生物。
Probably the most dangerous creatures on Earth.
有你的宝贝。
There's your baby.
沃尔特和他的女人。
Walt and his woman.
不正是我心目中的保龄球馆。
Bowling alleys isn't exactly what I had in mind.
践踏它，直到冰雪融化，
Tread it till the snow melts,
然后加入出埃及记。
then join the exodus.
红灯！
Red light!
找坎普。
Looking for Kemp.
太多的形容词，太多的冷嘲热讽。
Too many adjectives, too much cynicism.
没有人在乎什么是错的，
Nobody wants what's wrong with the place,
他们只在乎什么是对的。
they want to read about what's right.
- 这是重写的。 - 是的，我注意到了。
- It's a rewrite. - Yeah, I'm aware of that.
而你也在其中，
And while you're at it,
你可能要重写标题，并称它为
you might want to rewrite the title and call it
“我爱波多黎各的十大纪事。”
"Ten Things That I Love About Puerto Rico."
所以
So,
清醒的未来如何？
how's the sobriety coming along?
我砍掉了。
I'm cutting down.
我的意思是酒瓶的大小。
By that, I assume you mean the size of the bottles.
是不是每个人都喝161的样品酒呢？
How does anybody drink 161 miniatures?
每周你要喝掉 93 瓶的样品酒。
You're averaging 93 miniatures a week.
他们一天要存放四次？
What, do they stock the place four times a day?
难道不是免费的吗？
Are they not complimentary?
坎普先生，不是的。
No, Mr. Kemp, they are not.
不只是酒还有长途电话。
And neither is wine and long-distance phone calls.
因此，截至周一，你不再是世外桃源的居民。
So, as of Monday, you are no longer a resident of the Xanadu.
是什么把你带进来的？
And what exactly brings you into the building?
我不要淡褐色。
Don't hazel me.
我拿到 X光片。  我活不到一个星期了。
I got the X-rays back. I got less than a week to live.
淡褐色吗？你在说什么，你这瑞典痞子？
Hazel you? What are you talking about, you Swedish twerp?
你知道，太超过了，你还有心肝吗？
You know, it may have crossed what's left of your mind
这里有一家报社在运作，
that I have a newspaper to run here,
所谓的消息来源。
that we have something called news going on out there.
至于你所担心的，
But as far as you're concerned,
我还不如对他妈的窗口看！
I might as well look out of the fuckin' window!
你来这里干嘛？
What are you doing here?
这是报社，这里不需你要。
This is a newspaper. There's nothing here for you.
拿两个铲子来，别想从我这里挖出东西来。
Two of the best scoops you ever had came out of my brain.
你讲话最好客气点，否则我到别家去。
And you better moderate your language or I'll go elsewhere.
别家？ 你找不到工作的。
Elsewhere where? You couldn't get work as a fly repellent.
你一文不值，默巴克。
You're worthless, Moburg.
你玩完了。
The last onion in the jar.
不要推我，莱特曼。
Don't push me, Letterman.
推我是很危险的。
I'm dangerous when pushed.
我知道你为什么还在这里。
I know why you're here.
为了奖金。
It's payday.
依你的情况，奖金是被延期的。
But in your case, deferred on a permanent basis.
你被解雇了！
You're fired!
你不能开除我。
You can't fire me.
你欠我的工资。
You owe me money.
你最好付清，不然我就告到上头。
And you better pay it, or I'll come through the roof
让这事变成保险索赔。
and turn this place into an insurance claim.
你在威胁我？
Are you threatening me?
嘿，老兄，我们好好谈。
Hey, guys, let's take it easy.
你想试试巫毒术吗？
You want to suffer some voodoo?
你这痞子！
You twerp!
吃亡命丸去吧，莱特曼！
Eat the death pill, Letterman!
来吧，我们走。
Come on, we're walking.
你听到他说我什么吗？
Did you hear what he said to me?
这家伙，让我血压上升。
This guy's my blood pressure.
这家伙会把我气死。
This guy's going to kill me.
我要消毁那张照片！
And I want the negative of that picture destroyed!
我不想这畜牲在这里。
I don't want that animal in this building again.
他是肮脏卑鄙的小人。
He is hygienically unacceptable.
你看到他的鼻侧吗？
Did you see the side of his nose?
黑的就像个瞎子。
Blackheads like Braille.
他们应该放下他。
They should have him put down.
让默巴克成为历史。
Moburg is history.
早期他在这里是有机会的。
He's out of here at the earliest opportunity.
早期的机运。
And the earliest opportunity
是你。
is you.
你明白我的意思，坎普吗？
You understand what I'm saying, Kemp?
我了解你的论点。
I think I get the drift.
我要你在这文件下功夫，
I want you to immerse yourself into this paper,
因为你是个人才，所以你一定会成功的。
'cause you got the talent and I think you got the will.
你造就它并一起茁壮。
You make it grow and you grow right along with it.
我不是最佳人选。
I'm not best placed to do that.
你以为是我让你重写占星术和保龄球馆的吗？
You think it's my intention to keep you on horoscopes and rewrites and bowling alleys?
事实上，我现在要启发你。
Matter of fact, I'm gonna move you right now.
坐出租车到机场去。
Take a cab to the airport.
迈阿密的市长来访
The mayor of Miami's coming in.
把他的形象做好。
Make him sound nice.
要有照片??和专访。
I want a picture and an interview.
去完成它，保罗。
Make it work, Paul.
你离开我们了吗？
You leaving us already?
如果市长这家伙还不现身，我会搬到公寓去。
I'm moving into an apartment if this mayor guy ever shows up.
他们不断的改“延迟”再“延迟”。
They keep changing "delayed" to "delayed."
你要吃点早餐吗？
You want to have some breakfast?
沙滩上的小龙虾吗？
Little lobster on the beach?
20分钟的路程。
Twenty minutes away.
听起来像是邀请，但我得等市长来。
Sounds inviting, but I got to wait for the mayor.
不来了。
Isn't coming.
取消。
Canceled.
飞机时刻板写的。
That's not what it says on the board.
再一分钟。
It will in a minute.
我问过迈阿密那边。
I just called Miami.
来吧，我们吃早餐去。
Come on, let's have some breakfast.
有两件事，你可能有兴趣。
I got a couple things might interest you.
我得打电话。
I better call in.
你可以在车上打。
You can call from the car.
好呀。是啊，谢谢。
All right. Yeah, thanks.
这里只有两个岛屿。
There's only two of those on the island.
也许三个。
Maybe three.
没有人告诉我，这里这么漂亮。
No one told me it was so pretty here.
赚钱的好办法。
God's idea of money.
你知道是什么让这里变成金矿的吗？
You know what makes this place a gold mine?
不存在的东西。
Something that doesn't exist.
怎么会？
How's that?
土地。
Land.
不够。
There isn't enough of it.
那些知道如何弄到金矿的人。
Those who know how to get it get the gold.
雪诺？
Chenault?
保罗和我们一起早餐。
Paul's joining us for breakfast.
看起来像是去吃午餐。
Looks like it's gonna be a lunch.
这是雪诺。
This is Chenault.
你们互相认识？
You two know each other?
不知道耶，也许在飞机上见过面。
I don't know, I thought maybe we met on the plane.
我不这么认为。
I don't think so.
有男友航空公司吗？
I flew Boyfriend Airlines.
告诉我，保罗，龙虾喜欢吗？
Tell me, do you like lobster, Paul?
你知道吧，我今天可能没有时间。
You know what, I might not have time today.
不知道司机为何这么久还没来。
I didn't realize the drive was gonna take so long.
你剩多少时间？
How much time you got?
在15分钟内，我迟到了。
In 15 minutes, I'm late.
我来切凤梨。
I'll cut up a pineapple.
你应该把衣服穿上。
You might want to put on some clothes.
她是裸体做日光浴的。
She sunbathes in the nude.
当地的居民故意晒黑，把它当做旅游一样。
A few of the over-tanned locals tend to treat it as a tourist attraction.
我不感到奇怪。
Doesn't surprise me.
我的意思是，这是非常雅致的方法。
I mean that in a very tasteful way.
这是一个私人海滩。
It's a private beach.
他们不会来这里的。
They shouldn't be here.
坐下，保罗坐下。我会替你叫辆车。
Sit down, Paul, sit down. We'll grab you a cab.
他叫哈利。
His name's Harry.
取名自一本书。
Got the idea from a book.
保罗，我想谈谈
Paul, I wanted to talk,
因为我要找的人是
because I'm looking for someone who can
须具有同化与矛盾的观点
assimilate contradictory points of view
能让大家口径一致。
and make them into one voice.
你是一个小说家，对不对？
You're a novelist, right?
谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
噢，得了吧。  八卦报纸多的是。
Oh, please. Newspapers are full of gossip.
我要找的人要能言善道，次日，就能翻盘。
I'm looking for someone who's good with words, next day, you turn up.
因为，我相信好运气，
And 'cause I believe in good luck,
我想，也许你有同感。
I thought maybe you were it.
我需要的是
What I need
眼光精准的那种人。
is someone with the right kind of eyes.
精准什么？
For looking at what?
精准那些。
Looking at that.
海洋的财富。
An ocean of money.
嘿，你来了。
Hey, you made it.
门在最后面。
Door at the end.
- 嘿。   - 嘿。
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿。  给我两分钟。
Hey. Just give me two minutes.
右转进去。
Walk right in.
好吧。
All right.
在你来之前，我试图把这里整理好。
I was trying to get the place shipshape before you arrived.
阿道夫希特勒的演讲？
Adolf Hitler Speaks?
不是我的。默巴克以前是纳粹。
Not mine. Nazi stuff belongs to Moburg.
默巴克住在这里？
Moburg lives here?
他的制服还留在这里。
He keeps his uniform here.
这一个月我还没见过他。
I never see him from one month's end to the next.
所以，你可以看到，这是相当宽广的。
So, you can see, it's quite spacious.
别看厨房里。
Don't look in the kitchen.
水关了。 水龙头有问题。
The water's off. There's a problem with the valve.
你说你有一台电视机。
Thought you said you had a TV.
我说我有一种电视机。
I said I kind of have a TV.
对面巷子里的家伙配备了电视，而我有望远镜。
The guy across the alley has a TV, I have binoculars.
他的妻子是聋哑人士。
His wife's deaf.
打开窗户，你能听到每一个字。
With the window open, you hear every word.
来了。
Here it comes.
水来了。
Water's coming up.
我注意到你卧室里的一些鸡。
I noticed you had some chickens in the bedroom.
公鸡。
Cockerels.
呃，我流汗全身油渍渍的。
Yeah, I'm sweating the grease out.
不要担心，我会把鸡移到我的房间。
Don't worry about them, I'm moving them to my room.
你养它们做什么？
What do you do with them?
- 吃它吗？    - 吃它？
- You eat them? - Eat them?
不。  我才不吃它。
Nah. I don't eat them.
加油，宝贝，加油！
Come on, baby, come on!
那里，咬那里！
Get in there, get in there!
加油啊！
Come on!
嘿，贸易风，我的孩子！贸易风！
Hey, on a trade wind, my boy! On a trade wind!
来吧，硬起来，那里，鲍比。
Come on, bump it up, there, Bobby.
碰...碰...  是的，先生！
Bump, bump, bump, bump. Yes, sir!
嘿。  他们叫它厄尔怪物。
Hey. They call him El Monstruo.
三年来未曾败过。
Say he's never lost a fight in three years.
来吧，我们离开这里。
Come on, we're out of here.
来吧，快... 直达车。
Come on, rapido, rapido.
嘿，嘿，哇...
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
来吧。来吧。推啊。
Come on. Come on. Go on.
我告诉你，我们继续坳，直到翻盘。
I tell you, we were on a roll til that thing turned up.
这是217元。
That's $217.
不错。
Not bad.
217元是载粪钱。
$217 is a shitload of money.
等同于载粪钱。
Relatively a shitload.
他们培训的费用很贵。
They're expensive to train.
我见过有人赢得2000元，1万，在北滩。
I've seen guys win 2,000, ten on North Beach.
1万元？
10,000?
他为什么不把厄尔怪物带去那里？
Why didn't he take El Monstruo down there?
你说的是希尔顿酒店附近。
You're talking the environs of the Hilton Hotel.
他们佩戴领结和光鲜的鞋子。
They wear bowties and shiny shoes.
无法企望戴那种帽子。
There's no hope for his kind of hat.
问题是，再次，那不是目标之一。
The question, again, is not one of goals.
我们为了实现这些目标。
We're for those goals.
手段之一。
It's one of means.
你宣称是否艾森豪政府...
Were you claiming that the Eisenhower administration...
洗刷这种耻辱能持续多久呢？
How long can this blizzard of shame go on?
看这忘恩负义的浑蛋，自称他自己很公正。
Look at this ingrate besotted with his own righteousness.
黑白分明。
Black is a very dark shade of white.
好的，非常感谢你，尼克森先生。
Well, thank you very much, Mr. Nixon.
我听不下去了。
I can't listen to any more of this.
说谎跟吃饭一样。
Lies like he breathes.
想像一下，你一生都是躺着过活。
Imagine spending your entire life lying.
神圣的基督。
Holy Christ.
从来没有变得更糟。
Never got worse.
唯一的可能性是，有一天你会比他更糟的
The only eventuality worse than him is you know that one day,
一些肮脏的妓女，就要现身了
some filthy whore-beast is gonna show up,
使他看起来像一个自由派。
make him look like a liberal.
尼克森是不可能赢的。
The only upside with Nixon is he ain't gonna win.
他的笑容。
He's got the grin.
他是不可能赢的。
He ain't gonna win.
爱尔兰这家伙会赢。
Irish guy's going to win.
但是，他们不可能让他活的。
But they'll never let him live.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
我做“恐怖占星术。”
I do "horror-scopes."
你说他不会来这里。
Thought you said he never came here.
他拿到过滤器了。
He's got filters.
那种过滤器？
What filters?
他越过百加得工厂的墙。
He goes over the wall at the Barcardi plant.
这种过滤器在最后蒸馏过程中用的。
These filters are the last in line in the distillation process.
内含火箭燃料用的乙醇。
They contain more ethanol than rocket fuel.
类似什么呢？
What's it like?
大脑的手。
A hand on the brain.
关闭的范围。
Off the scale.
470验证。
470 proof.
没有470这样的东西来验证酒精。
No such thing as 470 proof alcohol.
你可能会适度的要求。
Certainty you might be required to moderate.
在提取区域，禁止吸烟。
No smoking in the extraction area, if you please.
真是好笑。
Don't be ridiculous.
不是供大众的饮酒。
Not for the social drinker.
你有兴趣畅饮吗？
You want to quaff?
不要
No.
不是现在，我要写作。
Not right now. I got to write.
我有最后的期限。
I got a deadline.
他写些什么呢？
What's he writing?
他搬开石头去完成“美国梦”。
He's lifting the stone on the American Dream.
关尼尔海湾。
Guayanilla Bay.
哦，是呃。 那里很糟糕的。
Oh, yeah. it's bad down there.
你这样的主题，只能吸引少数的读者。
You might find such a topic attracts a limited readership.
只要一个就行。
Only need one.
送到莱特曼那里。
Taking it to Letterman.
是啊，我听说要点“好运气”？
Yeah. Did I hear somebody say "good luck"?
是啊，我早上要去那里。
Yeah, I went down there this morning,
实际上他不敢开除我，他只能空想。
he unfired me on a temporary basis, maggot that he is.
我想带些东西给莱特曼。
I'd like to bring something in to Letterman.
像幻灯片，“你他妈的”枪。
Like a slide-action, "fuck you" gun.
不要在这里喝。
Don't drink that here.
只是尼泊隆，老男童。
Just a nipperoo, old boy.
质量测试。
Quality test.
老兄，就像电影情节里的慢动作谋杀。
Man, slow-motion murder, just like they do in the movies.
看见他飘回来
See him flying back,
他娘的“枪炮在空中飞奔。
fuckin' arms flapping in the air.
好吧，妈妈。
Okay, mother.
抬头看，最后你面对的这边就是地狱！
Look upon the last face you'll see this side of hell!
碰！
Bam!
他倒下去，身体爆裂成肉块。
Down he goes, morsels of vital organs spinning off into flesh orbit.
碰！
Bam!
去他妈的屁眼。
There goes his asshole.
碰！
Bam!
去他妈的鸟蛋。
There goes his dick.
碰！ 碰！
Bam! Bam!
去他妈的，莱特曼！
Fuck you, Letterman!
你在他妈的B级电影里，我就是机器杀手！
You're in a B-fucking movie, and I am the death machine!
我们还要有阿道夫？
Shall we have some Adolf?
千万不要。
Definitely not.
上你的路，上你的路，默巴克。
On your way, on your way, Moburg.
嘿，我们有客人在。
Hey, we're expecting guests.
你说他正在写一本书。
I thought you said he was writing a book.
我在写一篇短文。
Said I was writing an essay.
我只要你闭嘴。
And it requires some shut mouth.
不要浪费时间在垃圾失败者的身上。
Don't waste your time on those junkyard losers.
这个国家建立在种族歧视和奴役制度。
This country was built on genocide and slavery.
我们杀光了所有的黑人，在这里
We killed all the black guys that were here,
然后，我们再运来新的黑人来
and then we shipped in new black guys of our own,
接着我们把耶稣带来，像酒吧间的肥皂。
and then we brought in Jesus, like a bar of soap.
走吧。
Let's go.
你知道的。
You know it.
我是宗教的新闻记者。
I am the religious correspondent.
滚开，你这个耶稣警察！
Fuck off with your Jesus Police!
如果“圣经”是上帝的书，他为何没给大家呢？
If the Bible's God's book, why didn't He give it to everyone?
我们宁可发钱来停车，却没钱给孩子吃。
"We give more money to parking meters than we do to kids to eat."
别这样看。  我已经做了研究。
Don't read me like that. I've done the research.
12,000吨铁桶锈蚀后，海湾充满了盐酸。
12,000-ton rust bucket went down in the bay full of hydrochloric acid.
残害海里所有的生物。
Killed off everything in the sea.
毁了渔民。让他们的孩子沦为捡垃圾。
Killed off the fishermen. Their kids are picking garbage.
好吧，别生气。
All right, don't get angry.
外面很热。
It's hot outside.
你要喝吗？
You want a Scotch?
好啊。
Yeah.
十年前...五。  五年前
Ten years ago... Five. Five years ago,
我可能会说，展望未来。
I might have said go after it.
现在我想听天由命。
Now I say go with it.
无可改变的。
There's nothing you can change.
有时候多说无益，并避免争吵。
Sometimes you just got to spew over the side and keep rowing.
像夕阳的余辉。
Into a nut brown sunset.
土地发出积怨的愤怒。
It's the land of multiple outrage.
在起床吃早餐前，已遭千践万踏了。
Thousands trodden on before you wake up for breakfast.
这已经不是新闻，这是商业的现实。
That isn't news, it's a commercial reality.
夕阳并不是他们的专利
And providing it isn't their sunset,
没有人想买他妈的五分之一股权。
nobody gives one-fifth of a fuck.
你低估你的读者。
You underestimate your readers.
我不这么认为。
I don't think so.
你也低估了我。
You underestimate me.
你告诉我，认真工作，这就是我想要的。
You told me to make it work, that's what I want to do.
风沿着拉容嘉的废话也能上报纸。
Wind down this La Zonga crap and make a newspaper.
告诉你实情。
Let me tell you some home truth.
报社是跪求银行才能撑到今天。
This paper's been on its knees to a bank since the day it opened.
像世上许多的报社
And like most every other newspaper on Earth,
资金来自广告收入。
it's financed by its advertising.
没有广告，不仅是有没有报社
And without advertising, not only is there no La Zonga,
更没有所谓的报纸，就这样。
there's no paper to put it in, so, thus,
有些事我们不能写。
there are one or two things that we don't write about.
换句话说，当作不知道。
In other words, nothing at all.
另一种说法，酌权处理。
In one other word, discretion.
你不是一个外国记者。
You're not a foreign correspondent
在遥远的外国土地上，这是美国。
in some far-flung foreign land, this is America.
这是波多黎各。
This is Puerto Rico.
这的确是美国。
This is America.
那些水管工人，平常从伊利诺伊
You think some plumber from Normal, Illinois,
搭船到这里来可节省高达25年的时间
saves up for 25 years to come here on a cruise ship
在景气不好的时候种植甘蔗园？
to read about bad times in the sugar plantation?
他们也不敢他妈的！
They don't give a fuck!
普通的老百姓不敢捣乱
The average guy don't rock the boat,
因为要依赖它。
'cause he wants to climb aboard it.
而我们的读者大都是被动的。
And our readership is vividly average.
他们不在乎谁是失败者。
They don't care who the losers are.
他们只在乎谁赢了。
They want to know who won.
谁赢得了碗
Who won the bowls,
他比赛赢了，玩角子机赢到锅子。
who won the races, who won the pot at the slot machines.
看着我，坎普。
Look at me, Kemp.
你没睡觉，你很清醒。
You're not sleeping, you're wide awake.
这就是“美国梦”。
And this is the American Dream.
因此，许多酒店，看不到海。
So many hotels, you can't see the sea.
你想看海就得通过检查进到酒店。
You can see the sea by checking into the hotels.
花钱看海吗？
Pay to see the sea?
就是这么一回事？
What's the matter with that?
你只能寄望在梦中。
You're paying to be in the dream.
这个很薄的木皮，坎普
There's a thin veneer, Kemp,
就是梦想和现实之间。
between the dream and the reality.
你唤醒他们，他们便向你要求钱。
You wake them up and the people might start asking for their money back.
你是老板。
You're the boss.
不全是。
Not quite.
社论政策只是本报拥有的梦想。
The editorial policy of this newspaper is owned by the dream.
噢，天啊。
Oh, God.
哦，我的妈呀。
Oh, Christ.
哦，天啊，看看那个。
Oh, God, look at that.
哦，天啊！
Oh, God!
哈尔？
Hal?
不，不，我是哈尔的朋友。
No, no, I'm a friend of Hal's.
我一直在寻找他的船。
I was looking at his boat.
它是一艘可爱的小美女。
She's a sweet little beauty.
你搭过吗？
You been aboard?
没有
No.
壮丽的小岛屿。
Great little island hopper.
我们都去过。
We've all been down on her.
是一个美妙的体验。
It's a wonderful experience.
你们提早来了。
You two are early.
你很幸福。
You got lucky.
是啊。
Yeah.
吉姆，见过吗？
Did you meet?
是啊，我们用第一个名字。
Yeah, we got first names.
亚特朱巴格，美国已故海军陆战队员，一位伟大的朋友。
Art Zimburger, late of the U.S. Marines, great friend of mine.
这是保罗坎普先生，纽约时报。
This is Mr. Paul Kemp, New York Times.
你是作家。
You're the writer.
保罗是小说家。
Paul's a novelist.
纽约时报。
New York Times?
他不知道你从哪里来。
He don't know one from the other.
紧跟着他。  这家伙是关键。
Just go with it. This guy's key.
关键什么？
Key to what?
我们要讨论的关键。
Key to the discussion we're about to have.
看那些痞子。
Look at those mothers.
跟我来，坎普。
Come with me, Kemp.
这是一个私人海滩。
This is a private beach.
我们没有要到海滩啊。
We are not on it.
没有，是我们的！
No, but we are!
我们才叫做是私人的！
And what we do is private!
现在他妈的滚！
Now get the fuck gone!
他妈的滚出去！
Get the fuck out of here!
再让我看到你，下次
I see your face again,
你就赏你一把12口径的霰弹枪，告诉你怎么做。
you're gonna have a 12-gauge shotgun telling you what to do.
谈谈撒旦...
Talking about Satan...
如果撒旦的国度是存在的，就是苏联。
if there ever was a kingdom of Satan, the Soviet Union is it.
只有这样，才能用共产主义去消灭它。
The only way to come to terms with Communism is to destroy it.
民主，要毁灭民主得先击垮美国才行。
Hit it before it hits us in a devastating democratic strike.
没有比这更重要。
No more for the major.
他们正在找一个执行的人
They're looking for a man to push that button,
我就是那个人。
I am that man.
是的，你，亲爱的。
Yes, you are, honey.
你真令人陶醉，香奈儿。
You look ravishing, Chenault.
谢谢。
Thank you.
你需要救援吗？
You need rescuing?
不要把他带走。
Don't take him away.
他非常有趣。
He's very entertaining.
我们在讨论古巴，不知道有没有偏离，没有吧？
We were discussing Cuba and, I don't know, we kind of veered off, didn't we?
保罗介绍我们一些自由派的观点。
Paul presents us with a somewhat liberal point of view.
有没有自由派这种东西呢。
There is no such thing as a liberal.
自由派的想法是来自一位共产党员的黑人学士。
A liberal is a Commie with a college education thinking Negro thoughts.
这是真实的事情。
Well, here's a fact for you.
所有黑人中有76.4％来自莫斯科的控制。
76.4% of all Negroes are controlled from Moscow.
这就是为何卡斯楚能这样轻易过关。
That's why Castro gets such an easy ride.
在我看来，我们应该用炸弹轰平古巴
In my view, we ought to bomb Cuba off the face of the Earth,
- 让他的人民活在和平中。 - 亚特。
- let its people live in peace. - Art.
嘿。来吧，让我们用餐去。
Hey. Come on, let's eat.
来吧。
Come on.
在阴暗处的家伙是谁呢？
Who's the guy in the shades?
西格拉的爸爸，是你在的等的人。
Segurra's Daddy. It's who you're waiting for.
谢谢你送我玫瑰。
Thank you for my roses.
没想到你有留意到。
I didn't think you noticed.
当然，我注意到了。
Of course I noticed.
保罗，你会介意加入我们的行列吗？
Paul, would you mind joining us?
先生，你好吗？
How do you do, sir?
- 坎普先生。 - 很高兴见到你。
- Mr. Kemp. - Nice to see you.
坎普先生。
Mr. Kemp.
好了。
Okay.
由我开始，这只是一个非正式的会议。
Let me just start by saying this is a purely informal meeting.
顺便说一下，你不用担心莱特曼，好吗？
And, incidentally, you don't worry about Letterman, okay?
莱特曼？
Letterman?
主要是纽约时报，关莱特曼什么屁事呢？
What the hell's Letterman got to do with The New York Times?
坎普先生为各种报纸兼职。
Mr. Kemp subs for a variety of newspapers.
偶尔，他会写写新闻。
Occasionally, he writes for the news.
他的业余时间是他的事。
What he does in his spare time is his affair.
这就是我喜欢他的原因。
That's how I like it.
我们希望你能为我们写一些东西。
We'd like you to do some writing for us.
因此，我搜集了。
So I gather.
关于什么？
About what?
在文章中，我们想要设置的东西
In a sentence, we want to set something up,
让公众成为我们的朋友。
and have the public as our friends.
我们有各种的方法，可以这样做。
And there are a variety of ways we can do that.
让我告诉你，这事该如何进行，保罗。
Let me tell you how this kind of thing works, Paul.
假设，例如，你想要把税提高5％。
Suppose, by way of example, you wanted to put up taxes by 5%.
聪明的做法
The smart way of doing it
是采浮动的10％加息法。
is to float the idea of a 10%o hike.
让大家都需要它，让自己小题大做
Let them all shout about it, get themselves in a fuss,
然后你提供优惠。
then you offer concessions.
“7％怎么样呢？” “不行”他们会说话。
"How about 7%?" "No way," they'll say.
好吧，留住友谊，就提高5％吧。
"All right, let's stay friends and make a compromise at five."
宾果。
Bingo.
他们认为他们赢了，那5％，你应摆在首位。
They think they won something, you get the 5% you wanted in the first place.
同样的道理也适用于房地产。
Same thing applies to real estate.
你想盖5栋房子
You want to build five houses,
你把规划申请为50栋。
you put in a planning application for 50.
你要盖多少？
How many do you want to build?
没有。
None.
我们要盖一个酒店。
We want to build one hotel.
好了，环顾这个地方
Well, looking around this place,
我想没人会注意到。
I don't think anyone would notice.
就在这里。
It isn't in this place.
在一个岛屿。
It's an island.
各种敏感的原因，我们不希望消息曝光。
Sensitive for a variety of reasons we don't want to get into now.
没有人希望天堂盖了酒店，但
Nobody wants a paradise choked with hotels, but
在一个妥协下大家都会很高兴。
everybody will be pleased to compromise at one.
这就需要靠聪明的写作
This is going to require some clever writing
去精心的布置所有的文章。
in various carefully placed articles.
那种事情是非法的吗？
Isn't that kind of thing illegal?
让我这样说，坎普先生，
If I may say, Mr. Kemp,
这是不恰当的评论。
that's an inappropriate comment.
岛屿在哪里呢？
Where's the island?
不能告诉你。
Can't tell you.
目前还不能。
Not yet.
自由裁量权是最重要的，坎普先生。
Discretion is paramount, Mr. Kemp.
如果你想加入我们，就必须签署一些文件。
If you want to join us, you'll have to sign some papers.
明天有一个会议，在哈尔的办公室。
We're having a meeting tomorrow in Hal's office.
如果你想了解那档事
If you want to be part of what will be
令人兴奋的计划，就来吧。
a very exciting project, come along.
有人开着滑稽的车在外面要找保罗。
There's a man outside in a funny little car for Paul.
哦，是的。
Oh, yeah.
先生们，请原谅我。
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me.
我要离开了。
I have to run.
不留下来吗？
Can't stay?
我听说美人鱼在月光下会出来。
I hear the mermaids come out in the moonlight.
我们见面的那一刻起，我就知道
From the moment we met, I knew
我们之间一定有搞头。
there was going to be something between us.
类似未婚夫那样。
It's called her fiancé.
天啊，我无可救药的坠入爱河。
God, I'm so hopelessly and progressively in love.
不要让爱情冲昏头
Do not confuse love with lust,
更不要酒后失身。
nor drunkenness with judgment.
你想听我的意见吗？
You want my advice?
不，如果涉及她的，不，我不要。
No. if it involves her, no, I don't.
远离她。
Stay away from her.
远离桑德森。
And stay away from Sanderson.
你在自找死路。
You're way out of depth.
我没对桑德森提供情报，让他去窃取岛屿。
I got no brief for Sanderson or his pissy rip-off island.
我只想要捻花惹草附带炒饭而已。
I just want some apple blossom lipstick and fucks.
你现在不承认。
You are in total denial.
她可是炒别人的饭。
She's fucking someone else.
据我所知，他们即将结婚。
And as I understand it, about to be married to him.
甚至不会邀请你。
You won't even make an invite.
真不敢相信。
I don't believe this.
我们言归正传。
We're right back where we started.
我们都见识过那些混蛋
That is the same Cabrones we passed
10分钟前。
ten minutes ago.
我们需要方针。
We need directions.
我们到那里吃点东西。
Let's get in there and get something to eat.
不
No.
不要，拜托。
Please, no.
我不会花一整天与罪犯在海滩上吃龙虾，
I haven't spent all day on a beach munching lobster with criminals,
我饿扁了。
and I'm starving.
两杯啤酒，两杯朗姆酒，一个牛排。
Two beers, two rums, one steak.
厨房已收了。
The kitchen is closed.
好吧，两杯啤酒和两杯朗姆酒。
All right then, two beers and two rums.
还有一份牛排。
And one steak.
已关了，先生 ...
Cerrado, Mister...
是呃，但我搞不懂那个。
Yeah, but let's not bother me with that.
那标示上说，餐点供应到午夜，我要一份牛排。
You got a sign down there saying, "Food til midnight," and I want a steak.
汗流浃背的妇女。
Girl of the swamp.
这提醒了我，我们需要地图。
Which reminds me, we need a map.
你知道我怎么想吗？
You know what I think?
我想我们喝太多的朗姆酒。
I think we're drinking too much rum.
有没有其他办法。
There's no other way.
我看到双层的烟灰缸和炒盐锅。
I'm getting double ashtray and double salt pot.
你醉得跟默巴克一样了。
You got a Moburg bifocal.
天啊，真是令人发指。
Christ, this is heinous.
试想一下，他为何会变成一个酒鬼。
Imagine what it must be like to be an alcoholic.
2元。
$2.
付完钱后离开。
You pay and you go.
我没有看到牛排。
I don't see a steak.
没牛排了。
No steak.
你是什??么意思，没牛排？
What do you mean, no steak?
我认为他的意思是牛排没有了。
I think he means no steak.
厨房已关了。
The kitchen is closed.
我无法为你服务。
I got no way of serving you.
听着，你不想听我抱怨糟糕的一天，
Listen, you don't want to hear about my bad day,
我不希望你那么严肃。
and I don't want no grave side out of you.
如果你无法做牛排，把牛排拿来。 我会生吃牛排。
If you can't cook it, bring it like it is. I'll eat it raw.
两块钱，付钱离开。
Two dollars, you pay and go.
别叼扰我。
Don't bother me.
你现在付，或者我叫警察。
You pay now, or I call the cops.
如果你没打算卖我牛排
If you have no intention of serving me steak,
你最好是给我滚开。
why don't you do your best to fuck off.
在我看来，气氛不妙。
It seems to me there's a bad vibe developing.
有些异样的眼睛盯着我们看。
There are one or two oddities giving us the eye.
不要固执。
Don't get paranoid.
他在打电话。
He's on the phone.
干嘛？
For what?
向餐厅订购？
Ordering food in a restaurant?
但愿他能直通联邦调查局。
Let's hope he's through to the FBI.
怎么一回事？
What's the matter?
你在笑什么？
What are you smiling at?
我没笑啊。
I'm not smiling.
我假装镇定啊。
I'm maintaining a casual face.
一个人刚走进来
A man just walked in
从负面的角度看，最好有充足的理由。
and has good reason for regarding us in a negative light.
- 我们？ - 我。
- Us? - Me.
他不久前见过我。
And he's just seen me.
他想找白人报复。
And he wants revenge on the white man.
你他妈的在说什么？
The fuck are you talking about?
那个有疤痕的家伙？
How about the one with the dent?
独眼龙吗？
The one with the eye?
很像。
The very same.
我们用走的还是用跑的？
Do we walk or run?
用走的。
Walk.
我来推动汽车。
I'll push the car.
我们走吧，希望他能高兴。
Let's walk and hope he's happy.
嘿，美国人。
Hey, Yankee.
美国人！
Yankee!
别让我看到后车的大灯。
Don't let me see headlights.
拜托别让我看到后车的大灯。
Please don't let me see headlights.
我看到后车的大灯了。
I just seen headlights.
踩油门。
Put your foot down.
你觉得究竟在哪里呢？
Where exactly do you think I got it?
你能开快些吗？
Can you go faster?
开快，我尽量。
Going fast as I can.
耶稣基督，老兄啊。
Jesus Christ, man.
我们会被杀！ 我们会被杀！
We're gonna be killed! We're gonna be killed!
嘿！
Hey!
为落跑做好准备。
Get ready to run.
从反方向落跑。
Run in opposite directions.
那桶给我！
Give me the brew!
给我他妈的酒桶！
Give me the fucking brew!
保罗！
Paul!
狗屎运。我刚才看到默巴克。
Piece of luck. I just saw Moburg.
至少我认为他看到了我们。
At least I think he saw us.
他们要上夜间法庭。
They got some kind of night court going.
他说，我们是禽兽
He says we were animals
醉酒又横冲直撞，
on a rampage of drunken anarchy,
把汽油浇在警察身上。
poured gasoline on one of his cops.
哦，我的天，我们注定要蹲苦牢。
Oh, my God, we're doomed.
你有话要说吗？
You have something to say?
是的，法官大人，我要。
Yes, Your Honor, I do.
首先，和我被铐的这家伙，我一生从没见过他。
Firstly, this guy handcuffed to me, I never seen in my life.
第二，我们要求有翻译的法庭。
And second, we'd like a translation of the charges.
你听到他们说什么吗？
You heard what they said?
恕我直言，我听到大家都讲西班牙话。
With respect, I heard people speaking Spanish.
你要什么语言，这个国家说的是什么语言，先生？
What kind of language do you think we speak in this country, Mister?
他跟我们不是一起的。
He's not with us.
警察要求他定罪。
The cops attached him to get a conviction.
你离开餐厅时有没有付钱？
Did you leave the Café Cabrones without paying?
你放火烧警务人员，有或没有？
Did you set fire to the police officer, yes or no?
不幸的是，法官大人，他凑巧给火喷到。
Unfortunately, Your Honor, he got in the way of our flame.
没错。
That's right.
不可能的，我们烧他的头上还能这样笑。
No way did we pour gasoline on his head and laugh as we did.
他说的可不是这样。
It wasn't like he said.
就像他说的吗？
Like he said?
如同你说的，你不会说西班牙语。
Like you say you don't speak Spanish.
坎普先生不会讲西班牙语。
Mr. Kemp doesn't speak Spanish.
那么，他会有充足的学习机会。
Well, he will have plenty of opportunity to learn.
对你的指控是很严重的。
The charges against you are grave.
拒捕袭警是要监禁一年的。
Resisting arrest carries a tariff alone of one year in prison.
跟使用致命武器攻击没有关系。
Never mind assault with a deadly weapon.
我打算把这个案件送到高等法院。
I'm going to refer this case to a higher court.
同时，我判决拘留30天等待候审。
Meanwhile, I remand you both in custody for 30 days.
如果可以的话，法官大人。
If I may, Your Honor.
来吧，桑德森先生。
Go ahead, Mr. Sanderson.
谢谢你，法官大人。
Thank you, Your Honor.
我无意要中断审判
It isn't my purpose to interrupt proceedings,
如果能将他们发回重审
but if the intention is to remand these gentlemen,
我谨要求暂时休会
I would respectfully ask for a brief recess
允许我向他们的律师联系。
to allow me to contact their counsel.
律师是谁呢？
Who is who?
阿尔弗雷多.昆。
Alfredo Quinones.
当然，有必要我会叫他起床的。
It would necessitate getting him out of bed, of course.
让你了解他们两位的重要性。
But given the importance of these gentlemen to
及各种利益关系。
various interests,
我确定，他会跟我一样很高兴来的。
I'm sure that he would be as pleased as I
在清晨3点来这里。
to come down here at 3:00 in the morning.
我们的保证金是多少呢？
How much did we cost him?
1,000美元。
About $1,000 apiece.
我不足以感谢你。
I can't thank you enough.
不要迟到。
Don't be late.
他妈的蛋！
Mother of balls!
总算有救援水车了。
We got to rescue the car.
不是现在。我们稍后再做。
Not now. We'll do it later.
我有一个会议要开。
I've got a meeting.
我没有时间了。
We do not have later.
他们12个小时前就开始了。
They've already had it 12 hours.
我知道那些混蛋是如何工作的。
I know how these bastards work.
他们可以在12分钟内拆下火车的轴心。
They can strip a train to axles in 12 minutes.
而且地上看不到油斑。
We'll be lucky to find an oil spot.
这还要等多久呢？
How long is this gonna take?
我怎么会知道呢？
How would I know?
我不能迟到。
I can't be late.
不知道你为什么急着想去。
I don't know why you're going at all.
那家伙的公司是很糟糕的。
That guy is bad company.
他是操控者。
He's a manipulative prick.
他操控我们免以牢狱之灾，没他行吗？
He manipulated us out of jail, didn't he?
现在，我们被他妈的控制了。
Now he fucking owns us.
我舌头像...
I got a tongue like...
绑了毛巾。
Like a towel.
想要喝啤酒吗？
Want a beer?
我像是要喝啤酒吗？
Do I want a beer?
不，我不要。
No, I do not.
我再也不要沾酒了。
I am never gonna touch alcohol again.
这车真他妈的通风。
What fresh hell is this?
前座不见了。
Front seat's gone.
该报销了，不是吗？
That's a write-off. isn't it?
你知道吧，我有一个绝妙的主意。
You know what, I've got a brilliant idea.
是什么？
What's that?
车轴的重量很重。
There's too much weight on the axle.
试着向前移动一下。
Try and move forward a bit.
要迟到了。
Gonna be late.
我要去一个星期。
I'm gonna be a week late.
你在做什么，萨拉？
What are you doing, Sala?
我突然意识到我是多么喜欢你。
I suddenly realize how much I like you.
什??么意思，你说我能干嘛？
What do you mean, what am I doing?
是车轴有些不对劲。
There's something wrong with the axle.
哦，我的天啊，被我们放火烧的警察。
Oh, my God, it's the cop we set on fire.
装做很正常。
Try and look normal.
靠右边！靠右边！
Make a right! Make a right!
- 怎么靠右边？ 无法靠右边。 - 靠任何一边！
- What right? There is no right. - Any right!
他来了。  保罗进来。
There he is. Paul, come in.
对不起，出点意外。
Sorry. There were unexpected developments.
我得回家，开始新的一天。
I had to go home and start the day again.
告诉我这件事。 有些日子是渡日如年。
Tell me about it. Some days are two sizes too small.
好吧，我怕有人要离开了。
Well, I'm afraid some of us had to leave.
但是，朱巴格先生你知道的。
But, Mr. Zimburger you know.
这是格林先生，国际第一海事银行。
And this is Mr. Green of First National Maritime Bank.
你要咖啡吗？
You want some coffee?
我认为我们该讲重点，哈尔。
I think we should move right along, Hal.
- 我得走了。 - 当然。
- I gotta go. - Sure.
坐下，保罗。
Sit down, Paul.
如你所知，坎普先生，
As you may know, Mr. Kemp,
岛上是由美国政府拥有的。
the island is owned by the U.S. government.
有部分范围现在归海军使用。
Part of it presently used as a target range by the Navy.
我们知道，据内部人士透露...
We know from internal sources...
这就是你打电话的目的？
Is that what you're calling me?
...政府正准备放弃租赁
...That the government is preparing to relinquish the lease,
这个地方有32平方英里将被释出
and this place wakes up as 32 square miles
宏伟又原始之地。
of magnificent and untouched real estate.
放眼看看。
Knock your eyes out.
在加勒比海没有比这更漂亮的海滩。
No prettier beaches in the Caribbean.
海滨环绕着一个美丽的小艇码头。
Orientated around one hell of a beautiful marina.
假设这是一间酒店的码头。
Thought it was one hotel.
我们先从酒店开始。
We start with one hotel.
就在你的脚下。
It's a foot in the door.
一旦我们开始运作，我们市场的公仆。
Once we're up and running, we're servants of a market.
- 像这里吗？ - 像这里。
- Like here? - Like here.
你看起来很担心，坎普先生。
You look worried, Mr. Kemp.
他不会担心。
He's not worried.
保罗和我共享一个微妙的夜晚。
Paul and I shared a tricky little night.
对吧，保罗？
Right, Paul?
虽然我们没什么睡。
Neither of us got much sleep.
我得走了，伙计们。
I gotta go, guys.
那么，我们也要离开了，先生们。
Well, we'll leave you gentlemen to it.
坎普先生签署文件了吗？
Has Mr. Kemp signed the papers?
现在签。
Doing that right now.
我一定要签吗？
What am I actually signing?
为了保密协定，互相信任。
Just a confidentiality agreement, affirmation of trust.
所以我们都坐在相同的按摩浴缸。
Just so we're all sitting in the same Jacuzzi.
如果一个粪浮出来，这样你明白吧。
In case a turd floats up, if you know what I mean.
来吧，保罗，我们来这里。
Come on, Paul, let's go over here.
给你。
Here you go.
只是技术性的问题，保罗。
It's just a technicality, Paul.
意味着你不能向任何人泄露该计划。
Means you promise not to talk to anybody about the project.
头好一点了吗？
How's the head?
很不舒服。
Unpleasant.
再次感谢你帮我保释。
Gotta thank you again for putting up the bail.
我能体会。
It's held on my cognizance.
但我认为这会让你丧失心智。
And I think it more than likely to slip various minds.
这个地方是钱海，保罗。
This place is a sea of money, Paul.
钱多的令人难以置信。
Unbelievable money.
几乎每一家大公司都把钱藏在海岸上。
Practically every major corporation hides its cash offshore.
不，谢谢。
No, thanks.
对我们来说是好消息
And that is good news for us,
因为我们就是海岸。
because we are the shore.
任何钱都不用进到波多黎各政府
Not one dollar that wings its way into Puerto Rico
去缴税款。
pays a cent in tax.
- 免税？ - 一毛钱也不用。
- Nothing? - Not penny one.
这包括化学公司
That includes chemical companies,
石油公司，矿业公司。
oil companies, mining companies.
价值120亿美元的铜矿
There's $12 billion worth of copper
从这里不到20英里的山区里。
in mountains less than 20 miles from here.
几十亿美元。
A dozen billion dollars.
像我这样的人
And there's people like me
才知道如何把它弄出来。
who know how to get it out.
所以，把合约签好。
So, putting it into context,
我可不想为了1,000元保释金，被打断骨头。
I don't envisage the breaking of bones to get at a thousand bucks.
因为你不在那里
Because you weren't here,
我同意你一个行程，以朱巴格的名义。
I agreed to an itinerary with Zimburger on your behalf.
你要在早上出发，希望没问题。
You'll be traveling down in the morning. Hope that's okay.
你需要什么，保罗？
What do you need, Paul?
只是在上下文里朱巴格的东西
Well, just in the context of this Zimburger thing,
你认为有提前的可能性吗？
do you think there's a possibility of an advance?
我不想问，但莱特曼非常不稳定
I don't like to ask, but Letterman's pretty erratic
有关薪水的事，你知道的。
with the paycheck, you know.
我需要一辆汽车。
Need to get a hold of a car.
你没有车吗？
You don't have a car?
不太可靠。
Nothing too reliable.
此外，我必须找一个像样的地方住。
Plus, sooner or later, I'm gonna have to find a decent place to live.
好吧，这我们可以帮你。
Well, we can help you with that.
你回来后，我们将整理出你的观点。
When you get back, we'll sort you out something with a view.
卡罗，有什么在车库里呢？
Carol, what do we have in the garage?
不... 不是那个。
No, no, no, no, no, no, not that.
是呃，这很好呀。  好吧，谢谢。
Yeah, that's fine. Okay, thank you.
你有一辆车了。 她会给你车钥匙开车上路。
Got you a car. She'll give you the keys on the way out.
应该是500吧？
Feels like 500?
是啊。谢谢。
Yeah. Thanks.
保罗 ...
Paul...
你下午干嘛呢？
How's your afternoon?
写半版的星座。
A half-written horoscope.
帮个忙，你愿意吗？ 开车去海滩接香奈儿。
Do me a favor, will you? Drive out to the beach and pick up Chenault.
我要她6:00在家里的楼下等。
I need her downstairs by 6:00.
好的。
All right.
那么，是这一件呢？
So, this one?
或者是...
Or...
这一件呢？
This one?
这些是干什么用，一个派对？
What are these for, a party?
狂欢派对。
It's for carnival.
他没告诉你吗？
Didn't he say anything to you about it?
- 没有 - 你要来哦。
- No. - You've got to come.
我们都要上船去。
We're all going down on the boat.
他没有邀请我。
He didn't invite me.
嗯，这是不是他的狂欢节。
Well, it isn't his carnival.
这一件呢。
This one.
我喜欢另外一件。
I like the other one.
是的。
Yes.
喜欢这车吗？
Love this car.
他给你的吗？
Did he give it to you?
但愿是。
I wish.
加速快。
Fast.
你想小赌一下吗？
You want a little bet?
赌什么呢？
A bet about what?
看谁先尖叫。
That you scream before I do.
如果我先尖叫，会得到什么呢？
That I scream before you do, in relation to what?
那么，加速看看有多快？
Well, how fast does it go?
我不知道。
I don't know.
这才叫赌啊。
That's the bet.
我今天已经毁了一辆车。
I already crashed one car today.
没关系，我会坐在大厅等他的。
It's okay. I'll just go sit in the foyer and wait for him.
我如果我赢了呢？
What do I get if I win?
你做了，我就会让你知道。
I'll let you know if you do.
来吧，我带你回去。
Come on, I'll take you back.
天啊，他们从哪里拿到这个？
Christ, where'd they get this?
我不记得了。 我一直尽量避开莱特曼。
I don't remember. I've been slightly avoiding Letterman.
要谢谢我让你重获自由。
You have me to thank for your freedom.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我始终有种焦虑的感觉
I got a feeling of total anxiety
我试图把忧虑放在单一的，连贯在一起。
trying to put my anxieties together in a single, coherent lump.
我把车搞砸了。
I'm fucked without a car.
我搞到一辆车。
I got us a car.
雪佛兰停在楼下。
It's the Chevy downstairs.
那是桑德森先生的车。
It belongs to Mr. Sanderson.
那又如何？
So what?
我得走了，就这样。
I gotta go type this up.
我不知道到底是怎么了。
I don't know what's going on.
他吓坏了，我们少了12页。
He's freaking out and we're down 12 pages.
你最好给我完成！
You better frigging do it!
别让这肮脏的畜牲出现在这里。
I see your filthy animal face in here again,
我要把你关起来！
I'll have you locked up!
你负责的是那一部分，撒拉？
What part of the building are you creeping towards, Sala?
- 暗室。 - 警察在找你。
- Darkroom. - Cops are looking for you.
- 找我吗？ - 找你。
- Looking for me? - Looking for you.
还有报纸上你扮鬼脸的相片！
And it ain't just your mug in the paper!
糟糕的一天。
What a day.
糟糕的一周。
What a week.
我告诉你，我要离开这里。
I tell you, I'm out of here.
墨西哥过客的方式之一。
One way to friggin' Mexico.
听着，我明天的行程。 桑德森的岛屿。
Listen, I got a trip tomorrow. Sanderson's island.
- 不，不，不。 - 哦，亲爱的。
- No, no, no. - Oh, dear.
是格林的钱，和我要的狂欢节。
It's green money, and I'm thinking of cutting across for the carnival.
你知道他们在圣托马斯狂欢。
You know they got that carnival in Saint Thomas.
我知道。
I know.
你为何不跟我去？
Why don't you come with me?
把警察的事忘掉几天吧。
Give the cops a few days to forget.
是啊。乐趣嘛。
Yeah. Fun.
我们的人。 12英嫉拇笈冢海军在14英里的地方。
Our guys. 12-inch Naval, 14 miles out.
这里没有人住吗？
Nobody lives here?
没人住。
No one who's staying.
拉扎！
Lazar!
朱巴格先生。
Mr. Zimburger.
这是拉扎先生，我们多放网站的建筑师。
This is Mr. Lazar, our much put-upon site architect.
- 你好吗。 - 你好。
- How do you do. - Hello.
朱巴格先生，我想你知道。
Mr. Monk, I think you know.
我协助格林先生，第一海事银行。
I assist Mr. Green, First Maritime Bank.
这是坎普先生，纽约时报。
This is Mr. Kemp from The New York Times.
你的名字，你说什么？
What did you say your name was?
- 鲍勃撒拉。 - 是啊，撒拉。
- Bob Sala. - Yeah, Sala.
美国旅游作家协会。
From American Travel Writers Association.
坎普先生是为我们的宣传册做准备。
Mr. Kemp is preparing our brochure.
“希望你来感受这里。”
"Wish you were here."
啤酒在冷却器里，先生们。
Beer in the cooler, gentlemen.
隔壁房什么都有。
I have everything next door.
这是主要的酒店。
This and this are the main hotels.
22层楼。
22 floors.
海湾的监护人，可以这么说。
Guardians of the bay, so to speak.
颜色为什么不同呢？
Why the different colors?
蓝色是供市民，红色的是投资者。
Blue is for public dissemination, red is for the investors.
是啊。山中别墅，海洋公寓。
Yeah. Hill villas, ocean condos.
码头。
Marina.
停车场有2000个车位。
Parking for 2,000 cars.
没有道路啊。
There's no roads.
哎呀，拉扎尔，你忘了道路！
Damn it, Lazar, you forgot the roads!
我们正在建设。我们正在建设。
We're building them. We're building them.
我们吃午餐去。
Let's have some lunch.
上万的服务员，女佣，侍者，工友，职员。
10,000 waiters, maids, bellhops, janitors, clerks.
外加，胖妓女。
Plus, whores for the fat man.
很难相信他们会这样做。
Hard to believe they'd do it.
我和建筑师那种家伙谈过。
I was talking to that architect kind of guy.
他要去圣托马斯，如果你想搭便车。
He's going to Saint Thomas, if you want a ride.
什么时候？
When?
我怎么知道呢？
How do I know when?
等他把事情处理完。
When he's finished here.
你知道奥斯卡维德怎么说的吗？
You know what Oscar Wilde said?
他们知道价格决定一切
"They know the price of everything,
与价值无关。
"the value of nothing."
两杯朗姆酒。
Two rums.
我还以为你放弃了。
I thought you'd given up.
最后，意志力被击败了。
Finally beat my willpower.
来吧，咱们离开这里。
Come on, let's go here.
嘿，老兄！
Hey, mi amigo!
嘿，罗西的歌手。
Hey, Rosie's a singer.
保罗！
Paul!
哈尔在哪里？
Where's Hal?
- 船上。 - 船上吗？
- Boat. - Boat?
帮我找一下我的女友。
Help me find my girlfriend.
嘿！你好吗？
Hey! How are you?
留意你的脚步。
Watch your step.
- 谢谢你。 - 没事。
- Thank you. - All right.
- 我们过去。 - 谢谢你。
- There we go. - Thank you.
嗨。
Hi.
看看你。
Look at you.
好。拿一些香槟。
Good. Grab some champagne.
嘿，上尉。
Hey, Captain.
- 嘿。 - 嘿。
- Hey. - Hey.
你带撒拉去岛上了吗？
Did you take Sala to the island?
你不应该这么做，保罗。
You shouldn't have done that, Paul.
这就是为什么我们要有保密协议。
It's why we have a confidentiality agreement.
他是不感兴趣的。
He isn't interested.
他那张嘴像美联社一样。
He's got a mouth like an AP wire.
我搞不懂他来干嘛。
I just don't know what he was doing there.
我真他妈的，搞不懂他来这里干嘛。
And I sure as shit don't know what he's doing here.
我们不该闷闷不乐，你呢？
Not going glum on us, are you?
只是在思考。
Just thoughts.
什么书？
What's the book?
古航海员之诗。
The Rime of the Ancient Mariner.
它写于1797年一个瘾君子，科尔里奇。
It was written in 1797 by a junkie called Coleridge.
他说当时他25岁。
He wrote that when he was 25 years old.
一台打字机伴着我渡过10年的岁月。
I've been dragging a typewriter around with me for 10.
我却什么都没写。
I've written nothing.
你已写了一些书啊。
You've written some books.
没。
Nah.
它们没有声音。
They had no voice.
我不知道如何写自己。
I don't know how to write like me.
这一点我很懊恼。
I resent that.
不，我不得不说他人不错。
No, I really have to say he's all right.
我不得不承认。
I have to admit.
公平就是诚实的。公平就是合理的。
Fair is fair. Fair is fair.
下午真是谢谢你。
Thank you for the afternoon.
我们也许会在城里碰面。
Maybe we'll see you in town.
你要去哪里？
Where you going?
她的朋友在乐队里演奏。
Her friend's playing in a band.
我们要去看看。
We're gonna go check it out.
我们会去的。
We want to come.
我要改声明稿本。
I'll rephrase that.
我们不会去的。
We don't want to come.
会的，会去的。女生想跳舞嘛。
Yes, we do. Us girls want to dance.
你明天再跳。
You're dancing tomorrow.
狂欢是重点，早就安排好了。
What's the point of going to carnival if everything is preplanned?
我想跳舞，除非你不带我去。
I want to dance, and if you're not going to take me,
- 我跟他们去。 - 她陪你，哈尔。
- I'm gonna go with them. - She's got you trumped, Hal.
坐下。 你醉了。
Sit down. You're drunk.
还等什么？  大家一起走吧。
So what? So is everyone else.
来吧。
Come on.
来吧，我们去吧。可能很好玩的。
Come on, let's do it. it might be amusing.
哦，库达度。 小心。
Oh, cuidado. Careful.
到了。
Here we go.
噢，是啊。
Yeah.
累死了。
We're done. We're spent.
- 你要走了吗？ - 是的，我们要离开了。
- You're gonna go? - Yes, we're gonna leave.
你好了吗？
You're done?
跳不动了。真的。
I can't dance no more. Really.
等等。你知道吗？ 我叫香奈儿。
Hold on. You know what? I'll be out. Let me just get Chenault.
朗姆酒或啤酒呢？
You want rum or beer?
都要。
Both.
两杯朗姆酒，两杯啤酒。
Dos rum, dos cervezas.
- 哇，哇。 - 我们要走了。
- Whoa, whoa. - We're gonna go.
- 嘿。 - 我们要走了。
- Hey. - We're gonna go.
- 什么？ - 娜特莉离开了。
- What? - Natalie's leaving,
- 我们走了。 - 嘿，嘿。
- so let's go. - Hey, hey.
- 来吧，来吧。 - 不...。
- Come on, come on. - No, no, no, no.
香奈儿，到这里来。  离开了。
Chenault, come here. We're leaving.
- 香奈儿。 - 停止吧！
- Chenault. - Stop it!
香奈儿！
Chenault!
香奈儿，来这里！ 香奈儿！
Chenault, come here! Chenault!
把手拿开，操你娘！
Get your hands off me, you motherfucker!
他妈的，你敢动我！
You want to fuck with me?
知道我是谁吗？
You know who I am?
操你娘！
You motherfucker!
知道我是谁吗？
You know who I am?
- 你死定了！ - 走啊！走啊！
- You're a dead man! - Go! Go!
把手拿开。
Get your hands off me.
- 你死定了！ - 走啊！
- You're a dead man! - Go!
算了。
Forget it.
- 我帮你叫出租车。 - 滚开！
- We'll call you a cab. - Fuck off!
我必须去找她。
I gotta get the girl.
她玩得正爽。我们关门了。
She's having a good time. We closed.
你聋了吗？
You deaf?
我说，我们关门了。
I said we closed.
不行的，保罗。
No way, Paul.
不行的。
No way.
我到处找过了。
I looked everywhere.
我去找宪兵。
I went to the gendarme.
然后呢？
And?
我们去的地方。
We went up there.
没有人，那里没半个人。
Nothing. Nobody there.
只有，扫地的老妇人。
But an old woman with a mop.
找警察帮忙应该比较有效。
She was more help than the cops were.
我能做些什么，如果你的女友爱上别人呢？他说。
"What can I do if your girlfriend likes someone else?" he said.
他是对的，保罗。
He's right about that, Paul.
她不是你的女朋友。
She's not your girlfriend.
也许，她已回到船上了。
Maybe she went back to the boat.
你有去船上找吗？
Did you try the boat?
没有。
No.
我不认为他会让她回去。
I don't think he'd let her back on.
她是否跟你在一起？
Is she with you?
你何不把心思放在该死的公司呢？
Why don't you mind your own goddamn business?
我要钥匙。
I want the keys.
雪佛兰。
The Chevy.
你搞砸了，坎普。
You blew it, Kemp.
全生锈了。
It's all rust.
我有看到较好的轮胎悬在拖船的侧面。
I've seen better tires hanging over the side of a tug.
你要还是不要？
You want it or not?
是的，我们需要它。
Yeah, we want it.
每个人都改成周五在领钱，对不对？
Everyone turns up for their Friday check, right?
没得领钱，莱特曼不在。
No check, no Letterman.
所以，我去找他那又蠢又丑陋的老婆。
So I go around to see that unforgivably ugly wife of his.
她告诉我，他去了迈阿密。
She tells me he's gone to Miami.
为了什么？
For what?
你不知道，我不知道。
You don't know, I don't know.
但那些罢工者又回来了。
But the scabs are back.
由于玛丽欧走了，报纸又发生滞销。
Since Merell went, the paper took a turn for the worse.
有任何钓鱼用诱饵吗？
Is there anything in the spinner?
我们需要一个新袋子。
We need a fresh sack.
好吧，也许我能让那些人引起兴趣。
Well, maybe I can interest you gentlemen in something else.
类似什么，死亡吗？
Like what, death?
史上最毒的药物。
Like the most powerful drug in the history of narcotics.
我不是随便说说和臭屁。
I'm not at liberty to discuss or disclose.
我可以告诉你这东西毒性非常强大的。
All I can tell you is this stuff is so powerful,
让他们成为共产党员。
they give it to Communists.
谁呢？
Who does?
联邦调查局。
The FBI.
为什么联邦调查局会搞上共产党高层？
Why would the FBI get Communists high?
我无法告诉你。
That I can't help you with.
你把它像眼药水。
You take it like eye drops.
在眼？
In the eye?
所以，我明白了。
So I understand.
它让眼睛看得到。
It makes the eye see things.
你会看到一个不同的现实。
You see a different reality.
你想要干什么？
What do you want for it?
我会骑自行车把它扔进去，如果你能个忙。
I'll throw it in with the bike if you do me a favor.
有什么偏爱呢？
What's the favor?
我要你跟我来浴室。
I want you to come to the bathroom with me.
这男人是你的。
He's your man.
- 50元，对不对？ - 是啊。
- $50, right? - Yeah.
他要我看他的家伙。
He wants me to look at his dick.
我断然拒绝。
I flatly refused.
他要你看什么？
What does he want you to look at it for?
就说，一定有鬼。
Says there's something wrong with it.
这是君子做的事。
It's a gentleman's matter.
我不会看那档事！
I'm not looking at it!
好吧，把毒品还我。
All right, give me the drugs back.
不！等等。
No! Wait.
我来看看。
I'll look at it.
我会在镜子看。
I'll view it in the mirror.
有拍手吗？
Is it clap?
全场起立鼓掌。
A standing ovation.
你看到了什么吗？
You see anything?
没有。
No.
我也一样。
Neither do I.
我们再等五分钟看看。
We'll give it another five minutes.
还在裹足不前吗？
Trouble making ends meet?
- 然后，你需要的贷款吗？ - 对。
- Then, you need the Lending Man. - Right.
请打贷款人专线。
Call the Lending Man now.
从开始到现在多久了？
How long since we took it?
我不知道。
I don't know.
一段时间了。
A while.
开玩笑，不是吗？
Bullshit, isn't it?
是开玩笑吗？
Is it bullshit?
耶稣啊。
Jesus.
你的舌头就像是鸡、鸭的内脏。
Your tongue is like an accusatory giblet.
为了耶稣基督，不要伸出来。
For Christ's sake, keep it out.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你的舌头是撒旦的！
Your tongue belongs to Satan!
你灵魂出窍了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
不要伸出来！
Keep it out!
如果伸回到你的嘴里，就会身亡。
If it goes back into your mouth, it'll kill you.
我们开始在下沉了！
We've got to get it into the sink!
你让我忧心。
You're giving me fear.
别闹了！我很害怕！
Stop it! I've got fear!
你他妈的。我也是。
Fuck you. So do I.
你很high，你这个傻瓜。
You're high, you fool.
喝些朗姆酒。
Drink some rum.
我以为我在那里失控。
I thought I was losing grip in there.
我们该怎么因应？
What did we take?
我不知道。
I don't know.
我们需要拿到更多。
We need to get some more.
这不就说明了。
That explains it.
不是吗？
Doesn't it?
说明什么？
Explains what?
全世界。
The world.
和我们。
And us.
我惊讶的是，我们可能在不同的世界。
I wonder what it is you might think about our different worlds.
他看着我像似侧着身体说
He looked at me kind of sideways and said,
人类是地球上唯一的生物
"Human beings are the only creatures on Earth
声称是上帝。
"that claim a God.
唯一有生命的东西，其行为举止好像没有了。
"And the only living thing that behaves like it hasn't got one.
世界上没人拥有，除了你之外。
"Does the world belong to no one but you?"
而当他说话时，我大吃一惊。
And when he said it, I was taken aback.
不因为是谁在说话，
Not because of who was doing the talking,
因为我终于明白如何连接
because I finally understood the connection
孩子之间的觅食。
between children scavenging for food
及银行大门光亮的黄铜板。
and shiny brass plates on the front doors of banks.
得走了。
Gotta go.
进来。
Come in.
我们得走了。
We gotta go.
等我一分钟。
Give me a minute.
我在楼下等你。
I'll be waiting for you downstairs.
你来了真好。
How nice of you to drop in.
我被狂欢节淹没了。
I was covering the carnival.
这不是我所听到的。
That's not what I heard.
我听说你是在桑德森那里兼职。
I heard you were in the moonlight for Sanderson.
我曾经是？
I was what?
为桑德森兼职。
Moonlighting for Sanderson.
西格拉在哪里？
Where's Segurra?
西格拉先生不再与我们共事了。
Mr. Segurra's no longer with us.
我讲个故事给你听。
I got a story for you.
是的，你可能注意到我有点忙。
Yeah, you may have noticed that I'm somewhat busy.
这真的很重要，涉及西格拉先生和哈尔.桑德森先生。
This is real important, involving Mr. Segurra and Mr. Hal Sanderson.
我将告诉你有多么的重要。
I'm gonna tell you how important it isn't.
我在这行业干过21种工作和失败的报纸。
I got 21 jobs on the line and a newspaper going under.
印出这些，然后销售。
Print this, and you'll sell it.
一个策划的骗局。
A planning scam.
从字面上看天堂的掠夺。
Literally despoliation of a paradise.
千余人像垃圾一般被扫进大海。
A thousand people will be swept into the sea like garbage.
你很诡异，坎普。
You are weird, Kemp.
这不是他们要给什么，而是你要给他们什么。
It's not what it's doing to them, it's what it's doing to you.
这就是所谓的新闻学。
It's called journalism.
逗我笑。
Make me laugh.
我在求你戒掉豪饮。
I asked you to tidy up the booze,
你甚至无法清出一个房间。
you couldn't even sweep out a room.
你认为你还在这里工作吗？
Why do you think you're working here?
因为你的所作所为违反了记者的本份。
'Cause you're everything that's wrong with a journalist.
这一切的错对一家报社是耻辱。
And you're everything that's wrong with this insult of a newspaper.
一致同意。
Unanimously agreed.
你为什么不闭嘴，默巴克？
Why don't you shut it, Moburg?
你是浪费人类的精虫。
You are a waste of human sperm.
拖延死亡和死神不断地挣扎！
Die a prolonged and relentlessly agonizing death!
享用她。
Enjoy her.
泡了些茶。
Made you some tea.
你应该试着睡觉。
You should try and sleep.
我偷了你的床。
I stole your bed.
没关系。
It's okay.
我要写作。
I'm going to write.
我很抱歉。
I'm so sorry.
不要难过。
Don't be sorry.
你给了我从没有过的恩惠。
You did me the best favor I ever had.
这不是梦，香奈儿。
There is no dream, Chenault.
只是相怜相惜。
Just a piss puddle of greed,
在世界各地传播。
spreading throughout the world.
我要对读者作出承诺。
I want to make a promise to you, the reader.
我不知道，如果我明天能完成
And I don't know if I can fulfill it tomorrow
或者是还要多几天。
or even the day after that.
但是，我要把这个混蛋公之于世。
But I put the bastards of this world on notice.
我本身并没有获得任何利益。
That I do not have their best interests at heart.
我会详实的告诉我的读者。
I will try and speak for my reader.
这是我的诺言。
That is my promise.
这是油墨制成的愤怒之声。
And it will be a voice made of ink and rage.
坐下。我煮了咖啡。
Sit down. I made you coffee.
谢谢。
Thanks.
一份你的，一份我的。
One for you and one for me.
哦，伙计，我宁愿此事不是那样开始的。
Oh, man, I would rather not start the day with this.
- 这是什么？ - 是传票。
- What is it? - Lt's a writ.
这表示我们要上法庭。
Means we're going to court.
他们可以逮捕我们，正是他们希望的。
It means they can arrest us, should they so desire,
该死的时候，他们称心如意了。
any damn minute they please.
我们需要律师代言。
We need to speak to a lawyer.
我们连电话都没有。
We don't even have a phone.
我知道一个老家伙，西班牙的律师。
I know an old guy, Spanish Advocate.
欠我一份情。
Kind of owes me one.
你穿好衣服，我们现在就去。
You should get dressed. We'll go down there.
头发都是水，我满头都是肥皂。
Water ran out. I'm covered in soap.
他妈的，看我能做些什么。
Fuck it. See what I can do.
能做什么？
What's it for?
是哈尔。
It's Hal.
这件事是他指使的，现在他要打击我们。
He put up a bond for us on this thing, and now he's pulled it.
在这里。
Here.
你知道他是个骗子，保罗。
You know he's a crook, Paul.
而我们收到的传票。
And we get the writs.
那是什么？
What is it?
是希特勒的演说。
It's Hitler.
完蛋了。
It's over.
是什么？
What is?
他们想要我们死。
They shut us down.
他站在那里，公然向我们撒谎。
He just stood there and lied to us.
他是一个没道德观腐朽的收银机。
He hasn't got the morality of a clapped out cash register.
我不想告诉你这事，老兄，为了遣散费。
I hate to tell you this, guys, but it was to avoid severance.
我们都知道结果如何，查理。
We all know what it was for, Charlie.
- 那我们该怎么办？ - 一无所获。
- What are we gonna do? - Nothing.
我们无能为力，除非把他告到劳动局。
There's nothing we can do, except report him to the labor board,
这样做无济于事。
which is the same thing as doing nothing.
我不同意。
I disagree.
我们必须反击。
We gotta strike back
用指甲把这个混蛋抠出他的大门。
and nail this bastard to his own front door.
除了祈祷，我们该怎么办呢？
And how, pray, do we do that?
利用报纸。
By printing the paper.
我们拥有莱特曼极多的资源。
We got tons of stuff on Letterman.
与其人之道还治其人之身。
Every happy maggot with his hand in the till.
这是最终的难题，但我们得放手一搏。
It may be the last-ever issue, but we go out in a blaze of rage.
你在说什么？ 光成本就要2,200美元。
What are you talking about? It costs $2,200 a shot.
我们把罢工者带来。
We bring in the scabs.
让他们监督钱的事。
They're picketing for money.
你照照镜子。
You're through the looking glass.
我们连酒钱都不够。
We haven't even got enough money for drinks.
这不值得去斗争，课税已是长久以来的问题。
It's not worth the fight. This has been coming down the pike for a long time.
你应知道该结束时，就会结束。
You got to know it's over when it's over.
加勒比这小地方是搞不出什么名堂的。
This lousy little Caribbean rag is nothing but a wrapping for fish heads.
外加，它是封闭的。
Plus, it's a lockout.
封闭个屁。
Fuck the locks.
我说我们不得不行动。
I say we just walk in.
有人同意吗？
Anybody with me?
鲍勃？
Bob?
你知道我会的。
You know I'm with you.
我们还没缴电费。
We didn't pay the bill.
香奈儿在哪里？
Where's Chenault?
她去纽约了。
She's gone to New York.
她留给我100元。
She left me $100.
我敢不相信。
I don't believe it.
她身无分文。
She didn't have any money.
你应该跟她一起走。
You should use it to go with her.
红眼捐50块钱。
Red-eye for 50 bucks.
不
No.
我不会去任何地方。
I'm not going anywhere.
透过某些手段或方法，我要刊登在报纸上。
By some means or another, I'm gonna put the paper out.
报导这混蛋，然后我们走人。
Print the bastard, then we're gone.
面对现实，保罗。
Face the reality, Paul.
没有工作，没有钱，没有女人
There's no job, no money, no girl,
只有我们的逮捕令。
and a warrant out for our arrest.
什么都没得比。
There's no contest.
多诺万是对的，这是不值得斗争的。
Donovan's right, it ain't worth the fight.
我不是多诺万！
I'm not Donovan!
其他人也是一样。
And I'm not like the others.
我现在告诉你，下回那些滑头的蠢蛋。
I'm telling you right now, next time some greasy moron
再乱扯我，我会去照料他。
starts bullshitting me, I'm going after him.
美国总统一路上扬。
All the way up to the president of the United States.
我只想赢一次。
I just want to win one once.
一次。
One sheet.
你该不会用那100美元去赢。
You ain't gonna get far on $100.
有些罢工者成不了气候。
Some of the scabs will do it for nothing.
我们需要20个人员，再加上面包车。
We're gonna need 20 guys, plus vans.
不，不，你需要的是两大杯。
No, no, all you need is two grand.
朗姆酒没了。
We're out of rum.
仿佛上帝也感到厌恶。
It's as if God, in a fit of disgust,
我们要决心全力以赴。
has decided to wipe us all out.
是啊，公鸡三啼。
Yea, the cock crows thrice.
厄尔.麦思洛呢？
What about El Monstruo?
厄尔.麦思洛捐出100元。
Bet the $100 on El Monstruo.
你怎么知道他住这里？
How do you know he lives here?
我看到他出来过。
I saw him come out.
你最好让我自己来。
You better let me do this on my own.
如果是他的话，就带他去找巴巴尼波。
If he gets it, we should bring it to Papa Nebo.
是谁？
Who's that?
我的巫医。
My witch doctor.
她是一个雌雄同体。
She's a hermaphrodite.
停在这里！停在这里！
Stop here! Stop here!
白天，她开一辆垃圾车。
By day, she drives a garbage truck.
到了晚上，她变成巴巴尼波
By night, she becomes Papa Nebo,
往生者雌雄同体的灵媒。
the hermaphroditic oracle of the dead.
是巴巴山米迪的传人
When permission is granted from Papa Samedi,
墓地的门将
the keeper of the cemetery,
她会观察
she'll visit,
并挖出死尸。
and she'll dig up a corpse.
那些已僵硬的器官。
Certain organs of the disgrounded stiffs
是法事不可少的东西。
are indispensable for use in ouangas.
这是胡说，是不是？
This is horseshit, isn't it?
她治好了我的伤痕。
She cured my prick.
她想知道你要什么。
She wants to know what you want.
我们希望她能赋予这只鸡。
We want her to empower this fowl.
我们希望祝福它
We want it blessed
试图与它战斗的对手，都死了。
and anything that tries to fight it, dead.
把鸡带来。
Bring forth the fowl.
她说，世上没有任何一只鸡
She says that no fowl on Earth
可以挑战这只公鸡而存活。
could challenge this cockerel and survive.
很好。
Great.
她如何解除诅咒呢？
How's she off for curses?
问得好。
Pretty good.
我们对桑德森下咒，让他的鸡鸡断掉。
Let's have a curse on Sanderson. Make his dick fall off.
还有银行那个笨蛋，格林。
And that fucker at the bank, Green.
格林先生。
Mr. Green.
耶稣！
Jesus!
诅咒灵验了！
Curse active!
好耶，来吧。
Okay, come on.
一下，二上。
One down, two to go.
好了。我去打电话给默巴克。
Okay. I'm gonna call Moburg.
好吧。
Okay.
来吧。来吧。
Come on. Come on.
他不在那里。
He isn't there.
他应该要到。
He has to be.
他不在那里。
He isn't there.
- 你去哪里了？ - 对不起。
- Where have you been? - Sorry.
我没有听到电话。
I never heard the phone.
如何呢？
How's it going?
赢了，老兄。我们正在赢。
Winning, man. We're winning.
大伙儿都在那里吗？ 都在那里吗？
Ls everyone there? ls everyone there?
是啊，每个人都在这里。
Yeah, everyone's here.
那面包车呢？
What about the vans?
默巴克，面包车呢？
What about the vans, Moburg?
啊，是啊。对呃，面包车呢？
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, vans.
你听到了吗？
You hear that?
我们上路了。
We're on our way.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
他说，他是个男子汉。
He said he had the men.
“将向前业主索赔所有的 ... “
"All claims against the former owners will be..."
“签名代表海事第一银行，迈阿密。“
"Signed on behalf of First Maritime Bank, Miami."
桑德森的同谋，格林先生。
Sanderson's pal, Mr. Green.
对不起，保罗。
Sorry, Paul.
我不知道该怎么说。
I didn't know how to say.
他们把所有的机器搬走。
They took all the machines out.
不是全部，只有部分。
Not everything, but just the parts that matter.
我让你进来。
I'll let you in.
我想要的是一个头版。
All I wanted was a front page.
可能是最好的。
Probably for the best.
也许从来就没有关闭过。
Probably would've never pulled it off.
你们赢了多少钱呢？
How much did you guys win?
还不到六位数。
Just under six grand.
噢，是呃，好吧，你...
Oh, yeah, well, you...
至少够你还清债务。
At least you can pay off the bond now.
去他妈的债务。
Screw the bond.
我们离开这里。
We're out of here.
就这样结束了。
It's over with.
泛美有午夜班机。
There's a midnight Pan Am.
我不会去机场的。
I'm not risking the airport.
不会
No.
这个岛上欠我们一条船。
I figure this island owes us a boat.
我他妈的找桑德森理论。
And I'm fuckin' taking one of Sanderson's.
你闻到了吗？
You smell it?
感觉像那浑蛋。
It's the smell of bastards.
这也是真理的味道。
It's also the smell of truth.
我闻到油墨的味道。
I smell ink.
我得把鸡归还。
I got to take the hen back.
去寻找自己的归宿吧。
Find yourself a trade wind.
这是故事的结束也是另一个故事的开始
坎普最后回到纽约并与香奈儿结婚 成为美国最有名的记者
他发现正义之声是要靠自己的努力 如果你是那个“混蛋”你将有一个强大的敌人你自己
汉特.汤普森回忆录 1937-2005
= 全剧终 =